<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Jekyll Theme for Blogging</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 20:55:23 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 20:55:23 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Banks Don’t Reward Loyalty</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Most banks don’t reward loyalty so customers need to
haggle for a better mortgage rate or miss out on $850
a year in savings, the ACCC’s latest inquiry has found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ACCC Residential Price Inquiry has found that “only
11% of borrowers with variable rate mortgages had the
price of their current residential mortgage reduced by
one of the five banks under review in FY2018”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It found banks were generally not rewarding loyal
customers, but instead offering bigger discounts to
new customers coming on board.
“An existing borrower with an average-sized mortgage
could initially save up to $850 a year in interest if they
negotiated to pay the same interest rate as the average
new borrower,” the ACCC report says. “For many
borrowers the gain will be much larger.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it found that part of the reason for such a small
take-up — and why banks have not moved to reward
existing customers as much — was that it was hard to
get information on better rates, let alone change deals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/banks/rates/2019/01/16/reward.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/banks/rates/2019/01/16/reward.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Banks</category>
        
        <category>Rates</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Soft Landing Most Likely</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Sydney and Melbourne housing markets are “on track for a soft landing”. Long span of economic growth, 27 consecutive years, is likely to continue. The Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development says Australia’s long span of economic growth, 27 consecutive years, is likely to continue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its latest Australian economic survey, the OECD says:
“Life is good, with high levels of well-being, including
health and education. Robust economic growth is set
to continue. “New capacity coming on stream in the
resources sector will support exports and business
investment will pick up. Growth of wages and prices
will rise gradually, while the unemployment rate will
edge lower.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OECD says the most likely outcome for the housing
market in the biggest cities is a soft landing and that
a housing crash is unlikely. But it says the housing
market could pose a risk to the nation’s economic
growth going forward. “Financial supervisors and bank
regulators should be prepared in the event of a hard
landing in the housing market,” the report says. “High
indebtedness of households remains a risk.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/finance/prices/2019/01/15/oecd.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/finance/prices/2019/01/15/oecd.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Finance</category>
        
        <category>Prices</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Brisbane To Lead Rise in Units</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Brisbane’s recovering apartment market is set to lead the nation
over the next two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With values forecast to grow more than in
any other major capital city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moody’s Analytics expects apartments to outperform houses
throughout Greater Brisbane in 2019. It predicts apartment values will grow 2.8% in 2019, followed by
sharper growth of 6.5% the following year – a performance equalled
only by Darwin among the capital cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of specific sub-markets, a rise in unit values of more than
7% is expected in the inner city, Logan City and Moreton Bay regions
in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;House values are tipped to grow the most in Brisbane’s western suburbs this year (4.5%).
Moody’s Analytics is forecasting a 6% correction in house values in Melbourne this year, while Sydney house
values are expected to fall a further 3.3% in 2019 following a 5.2% drop last year.
The report says the cooling trend in the biggest cities in the final months of 2018 saw a sharper decline in
house values than for apartment values.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/city/brisbane/2019/01/14/brisbane.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/city/brisbane/2019/01/14/brisbane.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>City</category>
        
        <category>Brisbane</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lending Pick-Up</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Lending from the banks into the housing market will pick-
up after an easing of regulations across the sector. Frydenberg says regulations put in place by the
Australian Prudential Regulation Authority and recently lifted - are “building resilience” for the
future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He says that while the rate of growth in home
lending has fallen, the recent move by APRA to wind
back its intervention will soon be evident. “Now that
APRA has lifted some of its restrictions on investor
lending, we should see a pick-up,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frydenberg says targeted and short-term
¬interventions from APRA in the housing market
has, according to the RBA, ‘increased the resilience
of the economy to future shocks’. “However, now
these interventions have been wound back, it is
vitally important that the banks continue to provide
affordable and timely access to credit,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Keeping open their loan books to borrowers will help
maintain the strength of the Australian economy.”
According to the RBA figures, lending to owner-
occupiers grew 6.8% to an outstanding debt total of
$1.2 trillion. However, this is the lowest annual rate
of growth since the end of 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/bank/finance/2019/01/13/treasurer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/bank/finance/2019/01/13/treasurer.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Bank</category>
        
        <category>Finance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>QLD Pips Victoria For Migrants</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A stronger housing market and improving job
prospects has helped net migration levels to
Queensland overtake Victoria.According to a report from real estate group CBRE.
Victoria was Australia’s most popular state to move
to from 2013 to 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trend was supported by the state’s strong economy and buoyant jobs
market, with an average of 14,000 people per annum
making the change. But population growth eased in
FY2018, with falls in both net interstate and overseas
migration figures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deloitte Access Economics says that over the next
five years the Queensland economy is expected to
grow 3.6%, outpacing the 3% growth predicted in
NSW and Victoria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Sydney and Melbourne, people are being turned
off by the spike in property prices over the five years
to 2018. CBRE associate director Craig Godber
says the housing market will continue to support
migration to Queensland. “It has only been since
the price differential between Sydney and Brisbane
approached its widest point in early 2017 that a
clear upward trend in net interstate migration to
Queensland emerged,” says Godber.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/victoria/housing/2019/01/12/qld.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/victoria/housing/2019/01/12/qld.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Victoria</category>
        
        <category>Housing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Borrowers Reject Major Banks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Home loans by the major banks are growing at their
slowest annual rate in over 10 years. As banks tighten their serviceability criteria and more borrowers switch
to smaller lenders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Investment bank Morgan Stanley’s
analysis of lending data finds that annual growth in
home lending by the big four banks was only 3.6% in
November, while loans by the smaller banks grew 8%
and non-banks grew 16%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In our view, tighter lending standards are creating
a competitive disadvantage for the banks,” Morgan
Stanley analysts said in a research note.
Criteria used by the big banks to assess loan applications
has been criticised at the Royal Commission. That is
seeing a greater flow of customers to smaller banks
and non-bank lenders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some big lenders are, however, using their challenger
brands to compete in the investor loan market.
Commonwealth Bank has reduced the rate on investor
loans at subsidiary Bankwest, while Westpac has cut
a raft of investor interest rates across its St George,
Bank of Melbourne and BankSA loans.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/banks/finance/2019/01/11/banks.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/banks/finance/2019/01/11/banks.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Banks</category>
        
        <category>Finance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Prices Rise In 5 Capital Cities</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Prices rose in five of the eight capital cities in 2018,
according to the latest figures from CoreLogic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The growth was led by Hobart, where the Home Value Index
grew 8.3% last year. Darwin was up 3.7%, Canberra
3.6% and Adelaide and Brisbane were up by about 1%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The capital city average was a decline of 6.7%, according
to these figures, weighed down by a 10% fall in Sydney
and a 9% decrease in Melbourne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that other major research sources
disagree with these figures. The latest ABS data records
an annual decline in Sydney house prices, but by only
4.9% while SQM Research has Sydney down 5.8%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Melbourne, the ABS records an annual decline of
2.1% while SQM Research reports 1.8%, compared
to the 9% claimed by CoreLogic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Perth, the latest ABS figures report no change in House Price Index,
SQM Research reports an annual decline of 0.9%
while reiwa.com reported that the Perth median house
price rose slightly in both October and November and
remained unchanged in December. This compares with
CoreLogic’s claim of a 4.3% annual decline in Perth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/city/prices/2019/01/10/prices.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/city/prices/2019/01/10/prices.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>City</category>
        
        <category>Prices</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Banks Ease Squeeze On Lending</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The banks are easing their squeeze on new mortgages
with new loans to investors rising in October for the
first time since February, alongside an increase in
loans to owner-occupiers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The proportion of first-home buyers in the home loan market rose to
18.1%, a six-year high. There was a 2.3% rise in new
mortgage approvals in October, following falls in
the previous two months. The October rise was the
strongest growth rate since July 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Westpac senior economist Matthew Hassan says
the previous weakness in loan approvals may have
related to processing delays as lenders apply more
rigorous assessments. Loan approvals rose in all
states except WA, which suggests an easing in new
mortgage supply bottlenecks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In annual terms, loans in total are down 4.8%, mainly
due to the investor drop-off. But CommSec senior
economist Ryan Felsman says first-home buyers
continue to be very active.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The average home-loan size lifted in October, suggesting some buyers are
still gaining access to sizeable loans, despite tighter
lending standards,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/banks/rates/2019/01/09/loans.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/banks/rates/2019/01/09/loans.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Banks</category>
        
        <category>Rates</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Renovation Boom Hits Historic High</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Home renovations have hit a record high, sealing
2018 as the Year of the Reno for Aussie families.
Latest ABS data shows that private investment in
alterations and additions reached to a historic high
of $9.896 billion in the September Quarter, 11%
higher than a year ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Australia’s home renovations sector enjoyed its
busiest quarter in 14 years during the three months
to September 2018,” says MBA Chief Economist
Shane Garrett.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He says all signs are pointing to this figure rising
further, with many families deciding to renovate their
existing home rather than relocate to new ones.
“Australia’s home renovations industry may be
an unintended beneficiary of the tougher lending
policies,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Looking further out, we are almost certain to see
further gains for home renovations. More detached
houses were built in late 1980s Australia than at any time
before or since. More and more of these will be begging
for major renovations work in the coming years.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/home/2019/01/08/home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/home/2019/01/08/home.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Home</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>RBA Paves Way For Rate Cuts</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Reserve Bank has paved the way for further cuts to the official
interest rate. In a major speech this week, RBA deputy governor Guy
Debelle said the RBA was prepared to “go fast, go hard and not die
wondering” by stimulating the economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also said that a lending slowdown could hurt the economy, commenting: “There is a risk
that a reduced appetite to lend will overly curtail borrowing with
consequent effects for the Australian economy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Noting the Reserve Bank had “repeatedly” said the next move in
interest rates was more likely up than down, Debelle said there was
“still scope for further reductions in the policy rate”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It is the level of interest rates that matters and they can still move lower,” he said, in remark¬s that could
foreshadow a reappraisal of the outlook by the Reserve Bank board when it next meets in February.
The official interest rate has been unchanged since August 2016, when former governor Glenn Stevens
reduced the cash rate to a record low of 1.5% - the final in a series of cuts that has seen the rate fall from a
10-year peak of 4.75 per cent in late 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/banks/rates/2019/01/07/rba.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/banks/rates/2019/01/07/rba.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Banks</category>
        
        <category>Rates</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
